towson.edu 2019-12-11

# Privacy Statement | Towson University

Towson University is committed to protecting your privacy and personal information.

This privacy statement primarily addresses ways Towson University (“TU”) collects and manages both personally identifiable and non-personally identifiable information for users of its various websites and online portals. 

TU complies with both federal and state law regarding privacy rights. For example, as a state agency, TU does not create personal records unless the need for information is clearly established. Such records must be relevant to the purposes for which they are collected, be accurate and current, and not be obtained by fraudulent means. 

### Student Information

TU collects and retains relevant information, including “education records” as defined under the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (20 U.S.C. § 1232g; 34 C.F.R. Part 99) (“FERPA”), for both prospective and enrolled students. Its purpose is to further its mission, including providing successful academic opportunities throughout a student’s academic journey. Students’ education records are protected and not disclosed to third parties unless the student consents to the disclosure or a FERPA exception applies. Learn more about TU’s compliance with FERPA. 

### Data Collection Forms 

TU’s websites allow users to do things like request information, opt-in to receive messages/updates, register for events, purchase goods, and complete various tasks. To do so, TU uses electronic forms which collect necessary information, such as first and last name, address, phone number, and email address. This information is provided voluntarily and can be inspected and updated at a user’s request. 

### Cookies

TU uses various user-tracking technologies, including cookies, which allow it to collect and analyze user data. Information collected in this way includes how often a user visits a site, where users enter the site (e.g., by clicking on an advertisement or link on another web page), and what actions users take while on TU’s websites. TU utilizes this aggregate- and user-level site data to benchmark performance of websites and inform marketing strategies.   
Individual web browsers provide instructions on rejecting or deleting cookies. Please note some website pages and applications may not function properly if cookies are rejected or deleted. 

### Advertising

TU uses display advertising on other websites and search engines which measure performance and user behavior as it relates to those ads. Third parties, such as Google, Facebook, and YouTube, show TU ads to various audiences. These third parties then provide data to TU which helps it evaluate performance and assess user interactions before, during, and after visiting a TU website. To do so, TU places tags or pixels on its websites to capture information and inform interest-based advertising. 

### Security

Protecting personal information is our priority. TU takes appropriate and necessary actions to safeguard user information and personal records. It employs reasonable practices to help prevent the loss or misuse of data. Learn more about the university’s data privacy practices. 

### General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”)

Beginning May 25, 2018, the European Union (“EU”) will enforce data protection legislation known as GDPR, which requires TU to protect the personal data of EU residents. Protected personal data includes IP address, email address, and other device identifiers. TU is committed to processing personal data in compliance with GDPR. 

### Privacy Updates

This statement has been updated as of May 25, 2018. Additional updates will be added to this page. TU reserves the right to revise this statement at any time. 

### Questions

If you have any comments or questions about this Privacy Statement or would like to contact a TU representative regarding privacy or your personal information, please contact infosec AT_TOWSON.
